Nicole Paris: TEDYouth, make some noise!
نيكول: TEDYouth! أحدثوا بعض الضجيج!
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing)
TEDYouth, make some --
TEDYouth! أحدثوا بعض...
(Beatboxing ends)
(انتهاء الBeatboxing)
Are you ready?
هل أنتم جاهزون ؟
(Cheers and applause)
(تصفيق)
Ed Cage: Yeah, yeah, yeah!
إد: نعم! نعم! نعم!
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
EC: Y'all like that? Let me show you how we used to do it --
إد: هل يعجبكم هذا؟ دعوني أريكم كيف كنا نفعلها؟
NP: Get it pops, go ahead.
نيكول: هيا أرنا يا أبي!
EC: ... when I was growing up in the '90s.
إد: عندما ترعرعت في التسعينات
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing ends)
(انتهاء الBeatboxing)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing)
NP: Pops, pops, pops, pops, pops, pops,
نيكول: أبي! أبي! أبي! أبي! أبي!
hold up, hold up, hold up, hold up!
انتظر! انتظر! انتظر! انتظر!
Oh my God.
ياإلهي
OK, he's trying to battle me.
حسناً، إنه يحاول أن يواجهني
Hold on, right now, hold on.
توقف، الآن، توقف
Do you remember when you used to beatbox me to sleep?
هل تذكر عندما تفعل ال(beatbox) حتى أنام؟
EC: Yeah, yeah, I remember.
إد: نعم نعم أذكر
That's when she was a little baby.
عندما كانت طفلة
We would do something like this.
كنا نفعل شيئاً كهذا
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing)
NP: I remember that.
نيكول: أتذكر هذا
NP: All right, pops, pops, pops, chill out, chill out.
نيكول: حسنا يا أبي، اهدأ اهدأ
Hold up, hold up, hold up.
تريث تريث تريث
EC: Y'all remember the video.
إد: كلكم تتذكرون هذا الفيديو؟
This is like a little payback or something
هذا كرد الدين او ما شابه
for 50 million people calling me the loser.
ل٥٠ مليون شخص لنعتي بالفاشل
NP: Hold up, hold up.
نيكول: تريث تريث
But a lot of people out there don't really know what beatboxing is,
الكثير من الناس لا يعرفون ما هو الbeatbox
where it started from.
من أين بدأ
EC: Right, right.
إد: نعم نعم
NP: Where it came from.
نيكول: من أين بدأ
So why don't you give them a little history --
لم لا تعلمهم بعضاً من التاريخ؟
just a tickle -- a bit of history of where it comes from.
القليل فقط عن التاريخ ومن أين بدأ
EC: Beatbox started here in New York.
إد: بدأ الbeatbox هنا في نيويورك
(Cheers)
(تشجيع)
That's right, that's right. New York, New York!
نعم نعم "نيويورك" "نيويورك"
Everybody like, "Yeah!"
الجميع يصرخ "نعم" !
Well, we from St. Louis.
لكننا من "سانت لويس"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
NP: Now you can put y'all hands down.
نيكول: الآن يمكنكم إنزال أياديكم
EC: But beatbox started here in New York.
إد: بدأ الbeatbox هنا في "نيويورك"
What you would have is that, when we would go to parties,
ما كان يحدث هو انه عندما كنا نذهب الى الحفلات
you would have the DJ and you would have the rapper.
يوجد الDJ ويوجد الrapper
But because I don't have electricity coming out of me,
ولكن لأنه ليس هناك كهرباء تخرج مني
we had to emulate what the beats was doing.
كان علينا تقليد صوت اللحن
So when you would see the beatboxer,
عندما ترى الbeatboxer
you would see us over to the side.
كنا نحن بالجوار
Then you would see a rapper, and when the rapper began to rap,
وعندما يوجد الrapper وعندما يبدأ الرابر بالغناء
we would do a simple beat,
كنا نفعل لحناً بسيطاً
because back then the beats were simple --
لأنه في ذلك الوقت كانت الألحان بسيطة
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing)
or --
أو
Those were simple beats.
كانت ألحاناً بسيطة
But now, you got folks that want to do all type of stuff
ولكن الأن لديكم أشخاص يريدون فعل جميع الأصوات
with their beats now,
مع الألحان هذه الأيام
and they want to humiliate their father,
يريدون إهانة والدهم
which is not right when you want to humiliate the person
وهو فعل غير صحيح عندما تريد أن تهين الشخص
that take care of you, pay all your tuition, (Nicole laughs)
الذي اهتم بك ودفع تكاليفك الدراسية (نيكول تضحك)
especially when you have 50 million people
خصوصاً عندما يكون لديك ٥٠مليون شخص
that just go around and call you "the loser."
من حولك ينعتوك بـ"الفاشل"
Well, I'm taking that to heart.
حسنا، أنا أخذها الى قلبي
But now we do something different in our house,
ولكن الآن نفعل شيء مختلف في المنزل
so we have these jam sessions,
لدينا جلسات غناء
and our jam sessions consist of us jamming in church.
وجلسات غناءنا هي في الكنيسة
You know, in church, we'll look at each other like,
تعلمون، في الكنيسة ننظر إلى بعضنا هكذا
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and we'll text the beat to each other.
ونرسل ألحان إلى بعضنا
Or we'll be in the kitchen cooking,
أو نكون في المطبخ ونطبخ
road trips, airports.
رحلات برية، المطارات
NP: Standing right there in the corner, "Aw, Dad -- listen to that."
نيكول: أقف في الزاوية وأقول: "أبي استمع لهذا"
(Beatboxing)
(Beatboxing)
Naw, I'm kidding. But you know what?
لا، أنا أمزح، لكن أتعلمون؟
We're talking all about this jam session and everything.
نحن نتحدث عن جلسات الغناء وكل هذا
EC: Yeah.
إد: نعم
NP: Why don't we give them a little peek, just a tiny bit of our jam session?
نيكول: لم لا تعطيهم لمحة صغيرة؟ مقطوعة صغيرة فقط من جلسات غنائنا ؟
NP: Y'all want to hear some jam session? EC: Y'all ready for a jam session?
نيكول: هل تريدون الاستماع لجلسة غناء؟ إد: جاهزون للاستماع؟
NP: Sorry? I can't hear you.
(تشجيع)
(Beatboxing)
ابدأ يا أبي!
(Applause)
(Beatboxing)
NP: I'm getting ready to go!
نيكول: أنا جاهزة!
Get on up! Come on, stretch!
قفوا! هيا! تمددوا!
(Beatboxing ends)
(Beatboxing)
(Cheers and applause)
نيكول: هذا كل ما لدينا
NP: Make some noise! Make some noise!
إد: شكراً لكم جميعاً